## Bryan W. Weber

CONTACT INFORMATION Department of Mechanical Engineering University of Connecticut

191 Auditorium Road U-3139 Storrs, CT 06269 USA E-mail: bryan@engr.uconn.edu

Work: +1-860-486-2492 Cell: +1-412-443-6447 Web: bryanwweber.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests generally lie in developing tools to apply fundamental combustion insights to solve engineering problems. My recent work involves developing experimental methods to analyze intermediate species at practical combustion conditions. I am also interested in developing methods to analyze computational models, particularly kinetic models of combustion.

**EDUCATION** 

## **University of Connecticut**, Storrs, CT, USA

Ph.D., Mechanical Engineering, Planned Defense: May 2014 Working Dissertation Title: *High Pressure Ignition Chemistry of Alternative Fuels* Advisor: Chih-Jen (Jackie) Sung

M.S., Mechanical Engineering, August 2010

Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH, USA B.S.E., Aerospace Engineering, May 2009

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- **B.W. Weber**, W.J. Pitz, M. Mehl, A.C. Davis, E.J. Silke, and C.J. Sung. *Experiments and Modeling of the Autoignition of Methylcyclohexane at High Pressure*. Combustion and Flame, Feb. 2014. doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2014.01.018
- S.M. Sarathy, S. Park, **B.W. Weber**, W. Wang, P.S. Veloo, A.C. Davis, C. Togbé, C.K. Westbrook, O. Park, G. Dayma, Z. Luo, M.A. Oehlschlaeger, F.N. Egolfopoulos, T. Lu, W.J. Pitz, C.J. Sung, and P. Dagaut. *A Comprehensive Experimental and Modeling Study of iso-Pentanol Combustion*. Combustion and Flame, vol. 160, no. 12, pp. 2712-2728, Dec. 2013. doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2013.06.022
- **B.W. Weber** and C.J. Sung. *Comparative Autoignition Trends in Butanol Isomers at Elevated Pressure.* Energy and Fuels, vol. 27, no. 3, pp. 1688-1698, Mar. 2013. doi:10.1021/ef302195c
- T. Tsujimura, W.J. Pitz, F. Gillespie, H.J. Curran, **B.W. Weber**, Y. Zhang, and C.J. Sung. *Development of Isopentanol Reaction Mechanism Reproducing Autoignition Character at High and Low Temperatures*. Energy and Fuels, vol. 26, no. 8, pp. 4871-4886, Aug. 2012. doi:10.1021/ef300879k
- **B.W. Weber**, K. Kumar, Y. Zhang, and C.J. Sung. *Autoignition of n-butanol at elevated pressure and low-to-intermediate temperature.* Combustion and Flame, vol. 158, no. 5, pp. 809-819, Mar. 2011. doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2011.02.005

CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS AND PRESENTATIONS

- S.S. Merchant (Presenting), W.H. Green, K.M. Van Geem, N. Hansen, **B.W. Weber**, and C.J. Sung. *Combustion of the Butanol Isomers: Reaction Pathways from High to Low Temperature.* 8<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Chemical Kinetics, University Seville, Seville, Spain, July 2013.
- B.W. Weber, W.J. Pitz, C.J. Sung, M. Mehl, E.J. Silke, and A.C. Davis. Experiments and Modeling of the Autoignition of Methyl-Cyclohexane at High Pressure. Paper 3A02, 8<sup>th</sup> US National Technical Meeting of the Combustion Institute, Park City, UT, May 2013.
- **B.W. Weber**, S.S. Merchant, C.J. Sung, and W.H. Green. *An Autoignition Study of iso-Butanol: Experiments and Modeling.* Paper 3A01, 8<sup>th</sup> US National Technical Meeting of the Combustion Institute, Park City, UT, May 2013.
- S.M. Sarathy, S. Park, W. Wang, P. Veloo, A.C. Davis, C. Togbé, **B.W. Weber**, C.K. Westbrook, O. Park, G. Dayma, Z. Luo, M.A. Oehlschlaeger, F. Egolfopoulos, T. Lu, W.J. Pitz, C.J. Sung, and P. Dagaut. *A Comprehensive Experimental and Modeling Study of iso-Pentanol Combustion*. Paper 2A12, 8<sup>th</sup> US National Technical Meeting of the Combustion Institute, Park City, UT, May 2013.
- **B.W. Weber** and C.J. Sung. *Comparative Investigation of the High Pressure*Autoignition of the Butanol Isomers. Paper A-01, Fall Technical Meeting of the Eastern States Section of the Combustion Institute, Storrs, CT, October 2011.
- M.R. Harper, W.H. Green (Presenting), K.M. Van Geem, **B.W. Weber**, C.J. Sung, I. Stranic, D.F. Davidson, and R.K. Hanson. *Combustion of the butanol isomers:* Reaction pathways at elevated pressures from low-to-high temperatures. Paper #84, 7<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Chemical Kinetics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, July 2011.
- **B.W. Weber** and C.J. Sung. A Rapid Compression Study of the Butanol Isomers at Elevated Pressure. Paper 1B13, 7<sup>th</sup> US National Technical Meeting of the Combustion Institute, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, March 2011.
- **B.W. Weber**, K. Kumar, and C.J. Sung. *Autoignition of Butanol Isomers at Low to Intermediate Temperature and Elevated Pressure.* Paper AIAA-2011-0316, 49<sup>th</sup> Annual Aerospace Sciences Meeting, Orlando, FL, January 2011.

CONFERENCE POSTERS

- **B.W. Weber** and C.J. Sung. Validation of Kinetic Models of the Butanol Isomers At High Pressure using a Rapid Compression Machine. Poster T40, 7<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Chemical Kinetics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, July 2011.
- **B.W. Weber**. Autoignition of n-Butanol at Elevated Pressure and Low to Intermediate Temperature. 1<sup>st</sup> Combustion Energy Frontier Research Center Annual Meeting, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ, September 2010.

**B.W. Weber**, K. Kumar, and C.J. Sung. An Investigation of Hydrocarbon Flames using Probe Sampling and Gas Chromatography/Mass Spectrometry. Support of Undergraduate Research and Creative Endeavors Symposium and Poster Session, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH, April 2009.

OTHER PRESENTATIONS

**B.W. Weber** and C.J. Sung. *Analysis of Hydrocarbon Fuels using Gas Chromatography/Mass Spectrometry*. Summer Undergraduate Research in Energy Sciences Program, Dominion Energy East Ohio Branch, Cleveland, OH, August 2008.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Combustion Diagnostics Laboratory

2007-Present

University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT, USA

Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH, USA

Conducting experimental and computational studies of the ignition properties of several alternative fuels and foundational fuels, with focus on engine-relevant conditions. Designing a species sampling apparatus for time-resolved species measurements in the rapid compression machine, using gas chromatography/mass spectrometry to identify and quantify combustion intermediates. Analyzing kinetic models for combustion to determine the parameters controlling prediction of ignition delay and improve the ability of the models to predict combustion events.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## ${\bf University\ of\ Connecticut,\ Storrs,\ CT,\ USA}$

Spring 2013 — Instructor for "Introduction to Mechanical Engineering"

Supervisor: Kevin Murphy

Lecture notes and sample homework problems from this course are available on request

Fall 2012 — Teaching Assistant for "Combustion for Energy Conversion"

Supervisor: Chih-Jen Sung

Sample combustion modeling project assignments from this course are available

on request

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE Combustion Energy Frontier Research Center (CEFRC)

2012-Present

Lead Chair, Junior Associates Committee

Coordinate monthly teleconferences for graduate students and post-doctoral researchers in the CEFRC where junior members of the CEFRC present recent research results to the group. Act as the liasion between the Center's principle investigators and the junior members.

U.S. Department of Energy

2013-Present

Member, EFRC Newsletter Editorial Board

Contribute articles to the Energy Frontier Research Centers (EFRC) newsletter

describing recent scientific advances resulting from EFRC research, including: "Burning Butanol in a Better Engine"

"The Advantage of Renewable Fuels in High-Efficiency Engines"

The audience for the articles is scientifically literate, but not expert in the fields relevant to each article. Edit articles written by other board members for factual and grammatical correctness.

Journal Referee

2013-Present

**Energy & Fuels** 

Proceedings of the Combustion Institute

AWARDS AND FELLOWSHIPS Doctoral Dissertation Fellowship, University of Connecticut, 2014

Graduate Predoctoral Fellowship, Department of Mechanical Engineering, 2013 Graduate Teaching Fellowship, Department of Mechanical Engineering, 2013 Graduate Assistantship in Areas of National Need, University of Connecticut,

2010

Fred H. Vose Prize, Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, 2009 Summer Undergraduate Research in Energy Sciences Grant, Case Western Reserve University, 2008

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

AIAA - Student Member ASME - Student Member

The Combustion Institute - Student Member

ACS - Student Member